<rss version="2.0">
<channel>		 
  <title>Lawrence Logoh's blog</title>
  <link>https://lawrencelogoh.com</link>
  <description>Blog posts on Lawrence Logoh's blog</description>
  <generator></generator>

<item>
		<title>"Building a static site generator"</title>
		<link>https://lawrencelogoh.com/blog/2022-06-24-building-sgg.html</link>
		<pubDate>"2022-06-24"</pubDate>
		<guid>https://lawrencelogoh.com/blog/2022-06-24-building-sgg.html</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[    <article><p>What I was using is <ahref="https://github.com/lawrencelogoh/lawrencelogoh.github.io/blob/921d8d1012f73c6298b7d5412404b0f7b2a33ed/build">abadly written bash script that depends on pup and pandoc</a>. I don’tmind the pandoc dependency too much as I have it on all my systemsanyway. But the script is messy and I’d rather have somethingcleaner.</p><p>“Why not just use x?”</p><p>Most of the static site generators I’ve seen like Hugo and Jekyllseem too complicated for me. I’m not saying I can’t use them, I justfelt some friction and thought it would be cool to build my own.</p><p>My requirements for the current script were:</p><ul><li>Must have as few dependencies as possible.</li><li>Must work on UNIX/UNIX-like systems</li><li>Must generate an RSS file with all blog posts</li><li>Must arrange blog posts by date</li></ul><p>I didn’t put too much thought into how the old script worked. Istarted by writing a function that compiles the markdown files of myblog posts. Everything else came after that. Whenever I hit a roadblock,I looked for a program that could help me. In the end, I had a hackyscript that worked but I wasn’t proud of it. I also started to run intoproblems when I wanted to add new functionality or change something.</p><p><ahref="https://github.com/lawrencelogoh/lawrencelogoh.github.io/blob/9c27fe701fb522f936147f5ad5fbd01a02f7ad13/build">Thecurrent script</a> is not as bad. The way that it works is, it assumesevery directory(including the root directory) has an <code>src</code>subdirectory. It compiles every markdown file in the <code>src</code>subdirectories to HTML files that live in the directory itself. To getaway with not creating an <code>index.html</code> I create an<code>index.md</code> instead and that gets compiled like every othermarkdown file.</p><p>That’s the core of how it works. If you want the details, read thescript.</p><p>I’m happy with how it works right now but there’s a minor annoyance Ihave with it. The blog posts are arranged according to their dates byputting the date in the file name.</p><p><em>Yuck</em>.</p><p>I tried using an associative array to do it at first, but I found itdifficult to sort the dates with the sort program. I’ll figure it outeventually</p><p>If you have any suggestions email me or send a pull request:).</p></article>]]></description>
		</item><item>
		<title>"I failed my first live coding interview"</title>
		<link>https://lawrencelogoh.com/blog/2022-08-31-failed-interview.html</link>
		<pubDate>"2022-08-31"</pubDate>
		<guid>https://lawrencelogoh.com/blog/2022-08-31-failed-interview.html</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[    <article><p><em>Dear Lawrence,</em></p><p><em>Thank you for attending your interview with us.</em></p><p><em>Unfortunately we have chosen to not move your applicationforward…</em></p><p>This is part of an email I got shortly after doing a live codinginterview. The interviewer was really nice and it felt like theygenuinely wanted to see me do well. But I didn’t. And no, this wasn’t asuper hard coding question. It was an easier version of <ahref="https://adventofcode.com/2021/day/2">day 2 of advent of code2021</a> which I had done before. But for whatever reason, I wasn’t ableto produce a solution to the problem before my time was up. I had manythoughts after getting the email. &gt; “I should’ve done more leetcode”&gt; “If only I didn’t use python” &gt; “I would’ve seen the solution ifI didn’t panic”</p><p>Logically, I know it doesn’t matter too much. There will be many moreinterviews to come. But I still felt like shit.</p><p>Looking on the bright side. It wasn’t as scary as I thought it wouldbe. I think I’ll try a few more and see how it goes.</p></article>]]></description>
		</item>
</channel>
</rss>
