<rss version="2.0">
<channel>		 
  <title>Lawrence Logoh's blog</title>
  <link>https://lawrencelogoh.com</link>
  <description>Blog posts on Lawrence Logoh's blog</description>
  <generator></generator>

<item>
		<title>"2022 Review"</title>
		<link>https://lawrencelogoh.com/blog/2022_review.html</link>
		<pubDate>"2022-12-29"</pubDate>
		<guid>https://lawrencelogoh.com/blog/2022_review.html</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[    <article><p>Overall, this was a good year. Unfortunately, I wasn’t as productive as I had hoped to be. But, I learned a lot about myself and I made progress. I started learning Go and C, started some new projects, and even lost some weight. I also made some new friends along the way.</p> <p>While I’m happy with how the year went in general, I can’t help but feel like I could have done more. One of the big things I tried to learn was to not take things too seriously. It would feel like the world was ending if I forgot about some homework, for example. I feel like I took it a bit too far, but I think I’m ready to try a more <em>balanced</em> approach.</p> <p>I have a good feeling about next year.</p></article> ]]></description>
		</item>
<item>
		<title>"Plans for 2023"</title>
		<link>https://lawrencelogoh.com/blog/2023_plans.html</link>
		<pubDate>"2023-01-01"</pubDate>
		<guid>https://lawrencelogoh.com/blog/2023_plans.html</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[    <article><p>The basic idea behind this year is to play to my strengths and work on my weaknesses. Min-maxing essentially. A lot of these things are not checklist items that I can just list and tick off. They require step-by-step plans which I will make and follow.</p> <h2 id="productivity">Productivity</h2> <p>I already have a system that I use to manage my life. It’s just a folder of org files that I like to call my LMS(Life Management System). I plan to rethink and clearly define this system and some of the other systems that I use in conjunction with it. I think doing that will boost my productivity.</p> <h2 id="relationships">Relationships</h2> <p>When it comes to relationships, I’m very passive. I generally don’t call or text people until they call me and I don’t check on people I care about. When I talk to people about how they do it, they say it just comes naturally to them. For whatever reason, that doesn’t happen for me. But I want to do it, so I’m going to be more active and intentional about my relationships. This will involve not only calling and checking on people more, but also planning and scheduling activities to spend more time with the people I care about.</p> <h2 id="programming">Programming</h2> <p>I know some programming languages but I don’t think I know any of them well enough. So the plan is to become good at two of them at least. Python and Go seem like the obvious choices so I’ll go with them for now. While I do that, I also plan to at least check out Rust and Zig and see how I like them. When it comes to programming domains, I want to become a well-rounded backend developer and improve my frontend skills. Beyond that, I will be trying out other domains like mobile development and OS development(for fun). What this will generally look like is, building a lot of projects that are not necessarily useful to the general public. But if I can do that, I will.</p> <h2 id="money">Money</h2> <p>I’ve lived a very comfortable life. Because of that, I haven’t had to think about money until now. I want to do a lot of cool stuff but money seems to be the thing that I lack to do them. So this year, I’m going to focus on making money. My humble goal, for now, is at least an average income of $2000/month by the end of the year. I know I can make more than that, but I live in Ghana, and most employers don’t pay that much.</p> <h2 id="other-skills">Other skills</h2> <p>As you can already tell, my writing is shit. I want to write a book next year about a concept I’m chewing on, so it has to be improved. Another big one is some type of artistic outlet that is not writing. The ones I’m most attracted to right now are drawing and the electric guitar.</p> <p>This is a non-exhaustive list but these are the non-negotiables. They come first before everything else.</p> <p>Happy New Year.</p></article> ]]></description>
		</item>
<item>
		<title>"Building a static site generator"</title>
		<link>https://lawrencelogoh.com/blog/building_ssg.html</link>
		<pubDate>"2022-06-24"</pubDate>
		<guid>https://lawrencelogoh.com/blog/building_ssg.html</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[    <article><p>What I was using is <a href="https://github.com/lawrencelogoh/lawrencelogoh.github.io/blob/921d8d1012f73c6298b7d5412404b0f7b2a33ed/build">a badly written bash script that depends on pup and pandoc</a>. I don’t mind the pandoc dependency too much as I have it on all my systems anyway. But the script is messy and I’d rather have something cleaner.</p> <p>“Why not just use x?”</p> <p>Most of the static site generators I’ve seen like Hugo and Jekyll seem too complicated for me. I’m not saying I can’t use them, I just felt some friction and thought it would be cool to build my own.</p> <p>My requirements for the current script were:</p> <ul> <li>Must have as few dependencies as possible.</li> <li>Must work on UNIX/UNIX-like systems</li> <li>Must generate an RSS file with all blog posts</li> <li>Must arrange blog posts by date</li> </ul> <p>I didn’t put too much thought into how the old script worked. I started by writing a function that compiles the markdown files of my blog posts. Everything else came after that. Whenever I hit a roadblock, I looked for a program that could help me. In the end, I had a hacky script that worked but I wasn’t proud of it. I also started to run into problems when I wanted to add new functionality or change something.</p> <p><a href="https://github.com/lawrencelogoh/lawrencelogoh.github.io/blob/9c27fe701fb522f936147f5ad5fbd01a02f7ad13/build">The current script</a> is not as bad. The way that it works is, it assumes every directory(including the root directory) has an <code>src</code> subdirectory. It compiles every markdown file in the <code>src</code> subdirectories to HTML files that live in the directory itself. To get away with not creating an <code>index.html</code> I create an <code>index.md</code> instead and that gets compiled like every other markdown file.</p> <p>That’s the core of how it works. If you want the details, read the script.</p> <p>I’m happy with how it works right now but there’s a minor annoyance I have with it. The blog posts are arranged according to their dates by putting the date in the file name.</p> <p><em>Yuck</em>.<a href="#fn1" class="footnote-ref" id="fnref1" role="doc-noteref"><sup>1</sup></a></p> <p>I tried using an associative array to do it at first, but I found it difficult to sort the dates with the sort program. I’ll figure it out eventually.</p> <p>If you have any suggestions email me or send a pull request :).</p> <section id="footnotes" class="footnotes footnotes-end-of-document" role="doc-endnotes"> <hr /> <ol> <li id="fn1"><p>I have since implemented what I call “ghetto sorting”. It’s not pretty but it works<a href="#fnref1" class="footnote-back" role="doc-backlink">↩︎</a></p></li> </ol> </section></article> ]]></description>
		</item>
<item>
		<title>"Finding my Feet (January 2023 Review)"</title>
		<link>https://lawrencelogoh.com/blog/jan_2023_review.html</link>
		<pubDate>"2023-02-01"</pubDate>
		<guid>https://lawrencelogoh.com/blog/jan_2023_review.html</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[    <article><p>I haven’t made much headway with <a href="https://lawrencelogoh.com/blog/2023_plans.html">my goals for this year</a>. Most of the month was spent figuring out how to structure things. I’ve figured out some things about myself and some external factors have also changed. My school for example, decided to change the schedule of how school is going to be attended so I had to adapt.</p> <h2 id="productivity">Productivity</h2> <p>I significantly modified and streamlined my Life Management System(LMS). This has resulted in me doing more every week. There are still things I have to figure out about myself when it comes to working on personal projects. I have a pattern where I work in “bursts” and then I don’t do anything for a while. I’m going to try and see if I can work on things more consistently, but if I can’t I’ll have to find a way to use this to my advantage. There are other systems that I have added that are not public yet because they’re still being fleshed out. A Knowledge Management System(KMS) and a Zettelkasten that I will use to post things that don’t warrant a blog post.</p> <h2 id="relationships">Relationships</h2> <p>I managed to call people I normally would never call and I’ve added some reminders to call people so I don’t forget. I plan to continue this next month and do more. I’ve also scheduled group calls with friends, so I have people to talk to outside of family and work friends.</p> <h2 id="programming">Programming</h2> <p>I’ve started projects I call “boosts”. I pilfered the idea from <a href="https://github.com/rwxrob">rwxrob</a>. The general idea is they’re supposed to get me or someone like me to a point where they know and have used certain techniques. So in the case of python_boost, I’ve learned how to use decorators properly and I have a project where I’m going to use it so the general idea sticks in my head. They will be made available on <a href="https://github.com/lawrencelogoh">my github</a> so keep an eye out.</p> <h2 id="money">Money</h2> <p>Outside of <a href="https://www.fiverr.com/larrylogoh">Fiverr</a> I’m talking to some people but nothing concrete yet so fingers crossed.</p> <h2 id="other-skills">Other Skills</h2> <p>I suspect I’ve made zero progress here. When it comes to creative writing, I would classify it as a “wicked domain”, as described by David Epstein in Range. I’m not sure if becoming good, is a matter of deliberate practice alone but I’m sure it helps. I’ll read some books about writing and see what comes of it. I’ll also analyze writing that I like and see what I can take from them. In the case of the other creative outlet, I’ve made no progress there as well. I’m tempted to start making electronic music instead of waiting to get a guitar. If I don’t get an electric guitar by June I’ll start that instead.</p> <h2 id="school">School</h2> <p>I didn’t add this to my goals for this year because it wasn’t but I want to try harder at school. Yes, I’ve made a system for this too. I did have one already but it wasn’t clearly defined. I basically took notes and made flashcards that I studied a day to exams. I managed to get A+s in subjects I liked but did abysmally even in difficult subjects I liked.</p> <p>All in all, it’s been a good month but I’ll try to do better next month.</p></article> ]]></description>
		</item>
<item>
		<title>"Why OpenBSD?"</title>
		<link>https://lawrencelogoh.com/blog/why_openbsd.html</link>
		<pubDate>"2022-12-28"</pubDate>
		<guid>https://lawrencelogoh.com/blog/why_openbsd.html</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[    <article><p><strong><em>TLDR</em></strong></p> <p><em>It just werks</em></p> <p>I used FreeBSD as my main system for about a month and I love it. The speed, the Linux compatibility, jails, it’s beautiful. The only problem I had with it is, I had a lot of small problems. There would be these little problems, like not being to login to Twitch.<a href="#fn1" class="footnote-ref" id="fnref1" role="doc-noteref"><sup>1</sup></a> Or some programs like ncspot not working at all. OpenBSD doesn’t feel as snappy as FreeBSD and it doesn’t have Linux compatibility. But it works. Everything works the way I expect it to.</p> <p>So, I think I’ll be sticking with this as my main system for a while.</p> <p>If you’re curious, you can <a href="https://www.openbsd.org/faq/faq4.html#Download">get an image here</a></p> <section id="footnotes" class="footnotes footnotes-end-of-document" role="doc-endnotes"> <hr /> <ol> <li id="fn1"><p>This probably <a href="https://help.twitch.tv/s/article/supported-browsers?language=en_US">Twitch’s fault</a>.<a href="#fnref1" class="footnote-back" role="doc-backlink">↩︎</a></p></li> </ol> </section></article> ]]></description>
		</item>

</channel>
</rss>
