<rss version="2.0">
<channel>		 
  <title>Lawrence Logoh's blog</title>
  <link>https://lawrencelogoh.com</link>
  <description>Blog posts on Lawrence Logoh's blog</description>
  <generator></generator>

<item>
		<title>"Building a static site generator"</title>
		<link>https://lawrencelogoh.com/blog/2022-06-24-building-sgg.html</link>
		<pubDate>"2022-06-24"</pubDate>
		<guid>https://lawrencelogoh.com/blog/2022-06-24-building-sgg.html</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[    <article><p>What I was using is <ahref="https://github.com/lawrencelogoh/lawrencelogoh.github.io/blob/921d8d1012f73c6298b7d5412404b0f7b2a33ed/build">abadly written bash script that depends on pup and pandoc</a>. I don’tmind the pandoc dependency too much as I have it on all my systemsanyway. But the script is messy and I’d rather have somethingcleaner.</p><p>“Why not just use x?”</p><p>Most of the static site generators I’ve seen like Hugo and Jekyllseem too complicated for me. I’m not saying I can’t use them, I justfelt some friction and thought it would be cool to build my own.</p><p>My requirements for the current script were:</p><ul><li>Must have as few dependencies as possible.</li><li>Must work on UNIX/UNIX-like systems</li><li>Must generate an RSS file with all blog posts</li><li>Must arrange blog posts by date</li></ul><p>I didn’t put too much thought into how the old script worked. Istarted by writing a function that compiles the markdown files of myblog posts. Everything else came after that. Whenever I hit a roadblock,I looked for a program that could help me. At the end, I had a hackyscript that worked but I wasn’t proud of. I also started to run intoproblems if I wanted to add new functionality or change something.</p><p><ahref="https://github.com/lawrencelogoh/lawrencelogoh.github.io/blob/9c27fe701fb522f936147f5ad5fbd01a02f7ad13/build">Thecurrent script</a> is not as bad. The way that it works is, it assumesevery directory has an “src” subdirectory. It compiles every markdownfile in it to html files that live in the directory. To get away withnot creating an “index.html” I create an index.md instead and that getscompiled like every other md file.That’s the core of how it works.</p><p>If you want the details, read the script.</p><p>I’m happy with how it works right now but there’s a minor annoyance Ihave with it. I can’t arrange the blog posts by date except by puttingthe date in the file name. Yuck. I did try using an associative array todo it at first, but I found it difficult to sort the dates after withthe sort program.</p><p>If you have any suggestions email me or send a pull request:).</p></article>]]></description>
		</item>m
</channel>
</rss>
