<rss version="2.0">
<channel>		 
  <title>Lawrence Logoh's blog</title>
  <link>https://lawrencelogoh.com</link>
  <description>Blog posts on Lawrence Logoh's blog</description>
  <generator></generator>

<item>
		<title>2022 Review</title>
		<link>https://lawrencelogoh.com/blog/2022_review.html</link>
		<pubDate>2022-12-29</pubDate>
		<guid>https://lawrencelogoh.com/blog/2022_review.html</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[    <article><p>Overall, this was a good year. Unfortunately, I wasn’t as productive as I had hoped to be. But, I learned a lot about myself and I made progress. I started learning Go and C, started some new projects, and even lost some weight. I also made some new friends along the way.</p> <p>While I’m happy with how the year went in general, I can’t help but feel like I could have done more. One of the big things I tried to learn was to not take things too seriously. It would feel like the world was ending if I forgot about some homework, for example. I feel like I took it a bit too far, but I think I’m ready to try a more <em>balanced</em> approach.</p> <p>I have a good feeling about next year.</p></article> ]]></description>
		</item>
<item>
		<title>Plans for 2023</title>
		<link>https://lawrencelogoh.com/blog/2023_plans.html</link>
		<pubDate>2023-01-01</pubDate>
		<guid>https://lawrencelogoh.com/blog/2023_plans.html</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[    <article><p>The basic idea behind this year is to play to my strengths and work on my weaknesses. Min-maxing essentially. A lot of these things are not checklist items that I can just list and tick off. They require step-by-step plans which I will make and follow.</p> <h2 id="productivity">Productivity</h2> <p>I already have a system that I use to manage my life. It’s just a folder of org files that I like to call my LMS(Life Management System). I plan to rethink and clearly define this system and some of the other systems that I use in conjunction with it. I think doing that will boost my productivity.</p> <h2 id="relationships">Relationships</h2> <p>When it comes to relationships, I’m very passive. I generally don’t call or text people until they call me and I don’t check on people I care about. When I talk to people about how they do it, they say it just comes naturally to them. For whatever reason, that doesn’t happen for me. But I want to do it, so I’m going to be more active and intentional about my relationships. This will involve not only calling and checking on people more, but also planning and scheduling activities to spend more time with the people I care about.</p> <h2 id="programming">Programming</h2> <p>I know some programming languages but I don’t think I know any of them well enough. So the plan is to become good at two of them at least. Python and Go seem like the obvious choices so I’ll go with them for now. While I do that, I also plan to at least check out Rust and Zig and see how I like them. When it comes to programming domains, I want to become a well-rounded backend developer and improve my frontend skills. Beyond that, I will be trying out other domains like mobile development and OS development(for fun). What this will generally look like is, building a lot of projects that are not necessarily useful to the general public. But if I can do that, I will.</p> <h2 id="money">Money</h2> <p>I’ve lived a very comfortable life. Because of that, I haven’t had to think about money until now. I want to do a lot of cool stuff but money seems to be the thing that I lack to do them. So this year, I’m going to focus on making money. My humble goal, for now, is at least an average income of $2000/month by the end of the year. I know I can make more than that, but I live in Ghana, and most employers don’t pay that much.</p> <h2 id="other-skills">Other skills</h2> <p>As you can already tell, my writing is shit. I want to write a book next year about a concept I’m chewing on, so it has to be improved. Another big one is some type of artistic outlet that is not writing. The ones I’m most attracted to right now are drawing and the electric guitar.</p> <p>This is a non-exhaustive list but these are the non-negotiables. They come first before everything else.</p> <p>Happy New Year.</p></article> ]]></description>
		</item>
<item>
		<title>2023 Review</title>
		<link>https://lawrencelogoh.com/blog/2023_review.html</link>
		<pubDate>2023-12-31</pubDate>
		<guid>https://lawrencelogoh.com/blog/2023_review.html</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[    <article><p>The plan this year was to play to my strengths and work on my weaknesses. I ended up doing both very poorly.</p> <h2 id="productivity">Productivity</h2> <p>My Life Management System(LMS) is at the point where I can see myself using it for the rest of my life. It’s very simple and doesn’t really depend on any tools even though I only use it with emacs. There are a few issues like, using it on mobile but I think I can find an app that works reasonably well or make one.</p> <p>My productivity itself has been boosted. Not only because of the system but because I pushed myself and realised what I was capable of.</p> <h2 id="relationships">Relationships</h2> <p>I made a lot of progress here. I called people I care about a few times. Made time to just hang out where just being around friends was the goal. I checked on people a few times as well.</p> <p>In terms of romantic relationships, I tried. I generally don’t try but I tried this time. I was unsuccessful but I learned a lot not just about what I like but about the kind of person I am.</p> <h2 id="programming">Programming</h2> <p>So I programmed a lot this year. More than I did last year. But I didn’t do exactly what I planned to do. I planned to get better at Python and Go and try out Rust and Zig. I got a job where I mainly work with JavaScript so that became my main focus. I did learn Python and Go but not as much as I had planned to. I didn’t even touch Rust and Zig. I did do some mobile development but no OS development.</p> <p>I’m not happy with how this went, but I’ll try again next year.</p> <h2 id="money">Money</h2> <p>I didn’t get to my goal of $2000/month. I have however moved from making $0 to a respectable amount. I’ve also had to think about money a lot<a href="#fn1" class="footnote-ref" id="fnref1" role="doc-noteref"><sup>1</sup></a>. I’ve decided that I want a lot of it now and I’m going to try everything I can to get it without compromising my morals or ethics.</p> <h2 id="other-skills">Other skills</h2> <p>I’m not sure if my writing has improved or not. What I do know is that I’m not yet good enough so I’m going to keep trying.</p> <p>I haven’t practised drawing enough but I am practising.</p> <p>I didn’t buy an electric guitar but I have started learning how to use a DAW to make music. Music is the hardest thing I’ve had to learn so far but I will keep trying.</p> <hr /> <p>Overall, this was a good year. I’m not happy with how some things went, but I’ll learn from it and try to make next year better.</p> <section class="footnotes" role="doc-endnotes"> <hr /> <ol> <li id="fn1" role="doc-endnote"><p><a href="https://lawrencelogoh.com/blog/money_vs_passion.html">Money vs Passion</a><a href="#fnref1" class="footnote-back" role="doc-backlink">↩︎</a></p></li> </ol> </section></article> ]]></description>
		</item>
<item>
		<title>Plans for 2023</title>
		<link>https://lawrencelogoh.com/blog/2024_plans.html</link>
		<pubDate>2024-01-01</pubDate>
		<guid>https://lawrencelogoh.com/blog/2024_plans.html</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[    <article><p>The plan this year is to get good. I’m okay at a few things, but I need to get really good. I will write a detailed list of actions I will need to do to make this year a success but I’m not sure if I’ll release it publicly or not. We’ll see.</p> <h2 id="health">Health</h2> <p>This is going to be one of my main priorities this year. The goal here is to lose weight and get in shape.</p> <blockquote> <p>A healthy mind resides in a healthy body</p> </blockquote> <p>My mental health isn’t a big priority this year. I have a high baseline of happiness so we can leave that for another time. This doesn’t mean I will be neglecting it but it won’t be a high priority.</p> <h2 id="productivity">Productivity</h2> <p>My system is at a place that I’m really happy with. The focus now is to be to build habits that will help me be more productive.</p> <h2 id="relationships">Relationships</h2> <p>A lot of progress was made last year but there is still more to be made. The goal is to be more proactive and not just leave things to chance. Yes, this applies to romantic relationships as well.</p> <h2 id="programming">Programming</h2> <p>I’ve done a lot of learning when it comes to programming but very little doing. I’m still going to be learning but I’ll be writing a lot of <del>bad</del> software so that I can get better.</p> <h2 id="money">Money</h2> <p>The goal is the same as last year $2000/month.</p> <h2 id="other-skills">Other skills</h2> <p>This year, the main focus is on design. Mainly graphic design and UI/UX design. I will focus on writing and making music with a DAW as well.</p> <p>Happy New Year.</p></article> ]]></description>
		</item>
<item>
		<title>April 2023 Review</title>
		<link>https://lawrencelogoh.com/blog/apr_2023_review.html</link>
		<pubDate>2023-05-15</pubDate>
		<guid>https://lawrencelogoh.com/blog/apr_2023_review.html</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[    <article><p>Better late than never…right?</p> <p>This month was rough. I thought it’d be a piece of cake to handle school, work and personal projects. It wasn’t.</p> <h2 id="money">Money</h2> <p>It’s nice having a regular stream of income. It’s liberating in a way. Things I want to try out or buy don’t seem out of reach. I’ve been winging it when it comes to management though, so I’ll be taking it more seriously going forward.</p> <h2 id="productivity">Productivity</h2> <p>I had some health issues that lasted for about a week. This made it hard to get back into a rhythm but I figured it out eventually. I think I was sufficiently productive, but this is only true when it comes to work and school. My personal projects didn’t get any love. I think I’ve found my feet at work now so it shouldn’t be a problem going forward. My school workload is going to reduce next semester too so that should help.</p> <h2 id="programming">Programming</h2> <p>I haven’t made much progress on this outside of work. So my JavaScript skills have gone up, but that’s a consequence of working with it, not intentionally trying to improve. I intend to change that next month. I want to be more intentional about it.</p> <hr /> <p>Decent month.</p> <p>Not the best but I can only look forward and try harder. Hopefully next month will be better.</p></article> ]]></description>
		</item>
<item>
		<title>August 2023 Review</title>
		<link>https://lawrencelogoh.com/blog/august_2023_review.html</link>
		<pubDate>2023-08-29</pubDate>
		<guid>https://lawrencelogoh.com/blog/august_2023_review.html</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[    <article><p>This was a good month. It has been incredibly stressful but I was able to handle it.</p> <h2 id="productivity">Productivity</h2> <p>Satisfactory. Things are getting done.</p> <p>I’ve also been working on building some good habits. So far it’s going well.</p> <h2 id="relationships">Relationships</h2> <p>Progress has been made here. I’ve hashed out some issues I neglected. It feels freeing.</p> <p>It’s not perfect but the needle was moved.</p> <h2 id="programming">Programming</h2> <p>Progress was made but not as much as I would’ve liked.</p> <p>I haven’t been able to dedicate larger timeblocks due to other priorities<a href="#fn1" class="footnote-ref" id="fnref1" role="doc-noteref"><sup>1</sup></a>.</p> <h2 id="money">Money</h2> <p>No progress here but this is intentional. Trying to take on more work when I can’t will only hurt me.</p> <p>It can wait.</p> <h2 id="other-skills">Other skills</h2> <p>I’ve put a hold on this until I can dedicate time to them.</p> <p>When I engage in forms of escapism like watching YouTube, I try make it related to writing, music or other skills I’m interested in.</p> <hr /> <p>Overall, I feel good about this month. I can only hope it’ll increase my stress tolerance.</p> <p>Good job, Me.</p> <section class="footnotes" role="doc-endnotes"> <hr /> <ol> <li id="fn1" role="doc-endnote"><p>The biggest one being my final year project for university<a href="#fnref1" class="footnote-back" role="doc-backlink">↩︎</a></p></li> </ol> </section></article> ]]></description>
		</item>
<item>
		<title>Building a static site generator</title>
		<link>https://lawrencelogoh.com/blog/building_ssg.html</link>
		<pubDate>2022-06-24</pubDate>
		<guid>https://lawrencelogoh.com/blog/building_ssg.html</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[    <article><p>What I was using is <a href="https://github.com/lawrencelogoh/lawrencelogoh.github.io/blob/921d8d1012f73c6298b7d5412404b0f7b2a33ed/build">a badly written bash script that depends on pup and pandoc</a>. I don’t mind the pandoc dependency too much as I have it on all my systems anyway. But the script is messy and I’d rather have something cleaner.</p> <p>“Why not just use x?”</p> <p>Most of the static site generators I’ve seen like Hugo and Jekyll seem too complicated for me. I’m not saying I can’t use them, I just felt some friction and thought it would be cool to build my own.</p> <p>My requirements for the current script were:</p> <ul> <li>Must have as few dependencies as possible.</li> <li>Must work on UNIX/UNIX-like systems</li> <li>Must generate an RSS file with all blog posts</li> <li>Must arrange blog posts by date</li> </ul> <p>I didn’t put too much thought into how the old script worked. I started by writing a function that compiles the markdown files of my blog posts. Everything else came after that. Whenever I hit a roadblock, I looked for a program that could help me. In the end, I had a hacky script that worked but I wasn’t proud of it. I also started to run into problems when I wanted to add new functionality or change something.</p> <p><a href="https://github.com/lawrencelogoh/lawrencelogoh.github.io/blob/9c27fe701fb522f936147f5ad5fbd01a02f7ad13/build">The current script</a> is not as bad. The way that it works is, it assumes every directory(including the root directory) has an <code>src</code> subdirectory. It compiles every markdown file in the <code>src</code> subdirectories to HTML files that live in the directory itself. To get away with not creating an <code>index.html</code> I create an <code>index.md</code> instead and that gets compiled like every other markdown file.</p> <p>That’s the core of how it works. If you want the details, read the script.</p> <p>I’m happy with how it works right now but there’s a minor annoyance I have with it. The blog posts are arranged according to their dates by putting the date in the file name.</p> <p><em>Yuck</em>.<a href="#fn1" class="footnote-ref" id="fnref1" role="doc-noteref"><sup>1</sup></a></p> <p>I tried using an associative array to do it at first, but I found it difficult to sort the dates with the sort program. I’ll figure it out eventually.</p> <p>If you have any suggestions email me or send a pull request :).</p> <section class="footnotes" role="doc-endnotes"> <hr /> <ol> <li id="fn1" role="doc-endnote"><p>I have since implemented what I call “ghetto sorting”. It’s not pretty but it works<a href="#fnref1" class="footnote-back" role="doc-backlink">↩︎</a></p></li> </ol> </section></article> ]]></description>
		</item>
<item>
		<title>December 2023 Review</title>
		<link>https://lawrencelogoh.com/blog/dec_2023_review.html</link>
		<pubDate>2023-12-30</pubDate>
		<guid>https://lawrencelogoh.com/blog/dec_2023_review.html</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[    <article><p>This month was stressful. Not stressful in the sense that I pushed myself. Stressful in the sense that there were interpersonal issues that I had to deal with. It has made me question how I navigate relationships with other people.</p> <h2 id="productivity">Productivity</h2> <p>I wasn’t as productive as I was last month.</p> <h2 id="relationships">Relationships</h2> <p>I barely communicated with the people I care about.</p> <h2 id="programming">Programming</h2> <p>I also didn’t program as much as last month. There was a lot of planning but very little doing.</p> <h2 id="money">Money</h2> <p>Money was tight. Luckily, I don’t require that much money to survive now so I’m good. Next month will be better.</p> <h2 id="other-skills">Other skills</h2> <p>I tried to learn whenever it came up in my calendar. I missed some days but I’ll keep trying.</p> <hr /> <p>I managed to push through. I think next month will be better but we’ll see.</p></article> ]]></description>
		</item>
<item>
		<title>February 2023 Review</title>
		<link>https://lawrencelogoh.com/blog/feb_2023_review.html</link>
		<pubDate>2023-02-28</pubDate>
		<guid>https://lawrencelogoh.com/blog/feb_2023_review.html</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[    <article><p>I’ve made more progress than I did last month. Some areas are essentially “done” but what’s left is to build habits around them. I won’t talk about some areas but that’s because there’s either no progress or no notable progress.</p> <h2 id="productivity">Productivity</h2> <p>I’m happy with the current system I have. It does exactly what I want it to. I’m not fully used to all parts of it but that’ll come with time. One new thing I want to try is <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ghVdzAeX0bg">batching</a>. This is because when I work on things for extended periods of time(4+ hours) I feel more productive. The <a href="https://www.apa.org/topics/research/multitasking">task switching costs</a> for my normal days seem to be a lot of wasted time.</p> <p>In other news, my <a href="https://github.com/lawrencelogoh/kms">kms</a> is out. It’s empty right now, but I will be adding to it over time.</p> <h2 id="relationships">Relationships</h2> <p>The framework I use for this is satisfactory. It still feels uncomfortable and I don’t always follow through. My intuition is that this is because it’s a foreign thing for me, so I’ll try to power through and hope it gets easier with time. If it doesn’t I’ll have to make some modifications to the system.</p> <h2 id="programming">Programming</h2> <p>Programming is hard. I’ve realized that I know quite a few programming languages but I don’t know them well enough to use them in a real project. Case in point my project Homebase. I decided to use Go for this project but there was too much resistance when I was building it. It felt like I was fighting against the language. What I’ve decided to do is to build a <a href="https://github.com/homebaseorg/homebase-prototype">prototype</a> in Python first and then build the real project in Go. I am still doing my boosts of course, when I’m done doing them I will release them on Github.</p> <h2 id="school">School</h2> <p>The current system is good enough. I have taken a bit of a different approach of how I use it though. Normally, what I would do is I would try and fit exactly what the lecturer says or their slides into the flashcards. It worked but there was too much fluff so now what I do is, I “prune” my notes before making flashcards.</p> <h2 id="something-interesting-im-thinking-about">Something Interesting I’m Thinking About</h2> <p>I forget how I came across the concept of an <a href="https://pdos.csail.mit.edu/6.828/2008/readings/engler95exokernel.pdf">exokernel</a> but it’s been stuck in my head ever since. In simple terms, an exokernel is a minimalist operating system architecture that gives applications direct access to hardware resources for optimized performance and flexibility. From that, I’m sure a plethora of reasons come to mind about why this would be a bad idea. I just think it would be a fun thing to build.</p> <p>Overall, this month was better than last month.</p> <p>I wouldn’t mind if every month was like this</p></article> ]]></description>
		</item>
<item>
		<title>February 2024 Review</title>
		<link>https://lawrencelogoh.com/blog/feb_2024_review.html</link>
		<pubDate>2024-03-02</pubDate>
		<guid>https://lawrencelogoh.com/blog/feb_2024_review.html</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[    <article><p>Overall, this was an amazing month. I graduated from University, I bought a classical guitar and started learning how to play and I even lost some weight. This should be a good month on paper but I’m not happy about it. I think I could’ve done better.</p> <p>There’s also another issue I’ve been thinking about with these posts. It feels like it’s a bit too personal. I’m not sure how helpful any of this is to anyone or if anyone is reading them. So I’ve decided to publishing them and just keep them private for now. I was trying to “document not create” and it was nice for a while but I think I’m ready to create now.</p> <p>The website will get redesigned after a while and I will remove all posts like this one except the yearly plans and reviews.</p> <h2 id="health">Health</h2> <p>I was able to workout for about 20 days out of 29. I’m not happy about the number but it’s a step in the right direction. I haven’t had as much soda as I did last month and I have lost about 2KG of weight. Again, not happy, but it’s something.</p> <h2 id="productivity">Productivity</h2> <p>I’ve been able to do some habits but consistently but others, not so much. My morning and evening routines have been mostly consistent but the others have not been. I’ll keep trying but if nothing changes I will have to modify my approach.</p> <h2 id="programming">Programming</h2> <p>I was able to program on most days and I’m still learning about data structures and algorithms and ThreeJS. For data structures and algorithms I’m using the CRLS algorithms book and for ThreeJS I’m using the ThreeJS docs. My team lead at work also takes some time to teach me stuff about ThreeJS.</p> <h2 id="other-skills">Other skills</h2> <p>I’ve learned a bit about design and I’ve started learning how to play the guitar. For design, it’s mostly typography, and even the little I’ve learned makes me feel like redesigning the website. For guitar, I’ve created a playlist of cherry picked lessons that I follow and I also have another playlist of songs that I try to play.</p></article> ]]></description>
		</item>
<item>
		<title>January 2023 Review</title>
		<link>https://lawrencelogoh.com/blog/jan_2023_review.html</link>
		<pubDate>2023-02-01</pubDate>
		<guid>https://lawrencelogoh.com/blog/jan_2023_review.html</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[    <article><p>I haven’t made much headway with <a href="https://lawrencelogoh.com/blog/2023_plans.html">my goals for this year</a>. Most of the month was spent figuring out how to structure things. I’ve figured out some things about myself and some external factors have also changed. My school for example, decided to change the schedule of how school is going to be attended so I had to adapt.</p> <h2 id="productivity">Productivity</h2> <p>I significantly modified and streamlined my Life Management System(LMS). This has resulted in me doing more every week. There are still things I have to figure out about myself when it comes to working on personal projects. I have a pattern where I work in “bursts” and then I don’t do anything for a while. I’m going to try and see if I can work on things more consistently, but if I can’t I’ll have to find a way to use this to my advantage. There are other systems that I have added that are not public yet because they’re still being fleshed out. A Knowledge Management System(KMS) and a Zettelkasten that I will use to post things that don’t warrant a blog post.</p> <h2 id="relationships">Relationships</h2> <p>I managed to call people I normally would never call and I’ve added some reminders to call people so I don’t forget. I plan to continue this next month and do more. I’ve also scheduled group calls with friends, so I have people to talk to outside of family and work friends.</p> <h2 id="programming">Programming</h2> <p>I’ve started projects I call “boosts”. I pilfered the idea from <a href="https://github.com/rwxrob">rwxrob</a>. The general idea is they’re supposed to get me or someone like me to a point where they know and have used certain techniques. So in the case of python_boost, I’ve learned how to use decorators properly and I have a project where I’m going to use it so the general idea sticks in my head. They will be made available on <a href="https://github.com/lawrencelogoh">my github</a> so keep an eye out.</p> <h2 id="money">Money</h2> <p>Outside of <a href="https://www.fiverr.com/larrylogoh">Fiverr</a> I’m talking to some people but nothing concrete yet so fingers crossed.</p> <h2 id="other-skills">Other Skills</h2> <p>I suspect I’ve made zero progress here. When it comes to creative writing, I would classify it as a “wicked domain”, as described by David Epstein in Range. I’m not sure if becoming good, is a matter of deliberate practice alone but I’m sure it helps. I’ll read some books about writing and see what comes of it. I’ll also analyze writing that I like and see what I can take from them. In the case of the other creative outlet, I’ve made no progress there as well. I’m tempted to start making electronic music instead of waiting to get a guitar. If I don’t get an electric guitar by June I’ll start that instead.</p> <h2 id="school">School</h2> <p>I didn’t add this to my goals for this year because it wasn’t but I want to try harder at school. Yes, I’ve made a system for this too. I did have one already but it wasn’t clearly defined. I basically took notes and made flashcards that I studied a day to exams. I managed to get A+s in subjects I liked but did abysmally even in difficult subjects I liked.</p> <p>All in all, it’s been a good month but I’ll try to do better next month.</p></article> ]]></description>
		</item>
<item>
		<title>January 2024 Review</title>
		<link>https://lawrencelogoh.com/blog/jan_2024_review.html</link>
		<pubDate>2024-02-03</pubDate>
		<guid>https://lawrencelogoh.com/blog/jan_2024_review.html</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[    <article><p>This was a good month. I’m happy with how it went overall. Some things are still rough around the edges but they’ll all get ironed out in time.</p> <h2 id="health">Health</h2> <p>In this aspect, all tasks have been done. All that is left is for me to do things that I’ve decided on. For most of the month, as part of my morning routine I workout. It’s not a difficult workout, but it’s easy enough that I’m able to do it every day. I missed a few days because of what I’ll call “unforeseen circumstances”. On most days, I did them and I’m happy about that. I’ve cut out soda for the most part too. It doesn’t help that I recently discovered Monster Energy. And unfortunately, I love the taste. I thought Red Bull was good but Monster is something else. I try to have it once a week on my cheat day. I regards to weight, I did gain weight around when I started working out. It has started to go down again so I’m happy.</p> <h2 id="productivity">Productivity</h2> <p>I’ve started tracking my habits with org-habit. I’m trying to build habits of studying and programming everyday. My consistency is not at a level at which I like but I’ll keep trying.</p> <h2 id="relationships">Relationships</h2> <p><em>Scratches Head</em></p> <h2 id="programming">Programming</h2> <p>The studying habit encompasses this. I program everyday and I try to learn about programming everyday. This means I’m learning general things like data structures and algorithms but I’m also learning how to use specific technologies like ThreeJS right now.</p> <h2 id="money">Money</h2> <p>No tangible progress here yet. I’m trying a few things and if they don’t work, I’ll try other things. I believe I’ll cross the $1000 threshold for sure but I’ll need to put in some extra work for that extra $1000.</p> <h2 id="other-skills">Other skills</h2> <p>I haven’t learned much about design for some reason. The main thing I learned about this month was music. I think I got distracted along the way. I’ll course-correct and we’ll revisit this next time.</p> <p>I’ll try to do better next month.</p></article> ]]></description>
		</item>
<item>
		<title>July 2023 Review</title>
		<link>https://lawrencelogoh.com/blog/july_2023_review.html</link>
		<pubDate>2023-08-01</pubDate>
		<guid>https://lawrencelogoh.com/blog/july_2023_review.html</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[    <article><p>This is my worst month so far. The general theme has been “reactionary”.</p> <h2 id="productivity">Productivity</h2> <p>My productivity level is satisfactory. I’m not as disciplined as I want to be but I’m getting there.</p> <p>My Life Management System(LMS) is at a place I’m happy with right now. There might be slight tweaks in the future but I consider the project done. Expect an article on that soon :).</p> <h2 id="relationships">Relationships</h2> <p>This time I have negative feelings about this area. I didn’t make time for the people I care about. And I haven’t been straightforward with people.</p> <p>A regression, to be sure, but all I can do is try to be better.</p> <h2 id="programming">Programming</h2> <p>Progress has been made here. I have dedicated time to learning and I’m sticking to it as best as I can. The results will speak for themselves :).</p> <h2 id="money">Money</h2> <p>There has been no progress on making extra money. On the bright side, I’ve made progress on managing the money I do have. Speaking of money, most people seem really weird about it. Maybe “pocket watching” is the best way to describe it. It’s made me consider not talking about it publicly anymore.</p> <p>On the other hand, maybe it’s a good way to filter out certain people from my life.</p> <h2 id="other-skills">Other skills</h2> <p>I’ve downloaded Ardour and I’m playing around with it. Don’t expect an EDM album anytime soon though.</p> <p>I’m not sure how to gauge if my writing is improving or not. Maybe you can tell?</p> <hr /> <p>Overall, not a bad month, but not a great one either. I’ll try to do better next month.</p></article> ]]></description>
		</item>
<item>
		<title>June 2023 Review</title>
		<link>https://lawrencelogoh.com/blog/jun_2023_review.html</link>
		<pubDate>2023-06-25</pubDate>
		<guid>https://lawrencelogoh.com/blog/jun_2023_review.html</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[    <article><p>Halfway there.</p> <h2 id="productivity">Productivity</h2> <p>Considering where I was in January, I have positive feelings about this. I still use org files but things are a little different. I’m more confident with the system, and I’m doing more things. I haven’t necessarily been doing the right things, but again, progress has been made. There’s room for improvement.</p> <h2 id="relationships">Relationships</h2> <p>This is another one where I have positive feelings. I’ve called people I cared about and I made time for activities with them. I wasn’t as consistent as I wanted to be but again, progress.</p> <h2 id="programming">Programming</h2> <p>This is where things start to go downhill. I have improved, but not as much as I wanted to. On top of that, most of my improvement weren’t from deliberate learning, which I don’t like. I also have nothing to show for it outside of work. Radical change will need to be made for me to be happy with this.</p> <h2 id="money">Money</h2> <p>This is another one I’m happy about. I’m not making my goal of $2000/month. I’m not even making my goal of $1000 month. I still want to make $2000/month. My current job is flexible enough that it’s possible if I do more online gigs. Even if I don’t get to $2000/month, the fact that I’ve made progress makes me happy. It’s better than $0/month.</p> <h2 id="other-skills">Other skills</h2> <p>I’ve made zero progress in this area. I’m not sure how I feel about that. I think I can still make time for these things. I don’t think my writing has improved at all. There’s no excuse. I haven’t tried to actively improve. I haven’t bought a guitar yet, so I’m considering diving into EDM production and seeing how I like it.</p> <hr /> <p>I’m happy with how the year has gone overall but improvements can be made.</p></article> ]]></description>
		</item>
<item>
		<title>March 2023 Review</title>
		<link>https://lawrencelogoh.com/blog/mar_2023_review.html</link>
		<pubDate>2023-03-31</pubDate>
		<guid>https://lawrencelogoh.com/blog/mar_2023_review.html</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[    <article><p>This was a great month. I haven’t built as many great habits as I wanted to but I’m trying and these things take time.</p> <h2 id="money">Money</h2> <p>I landed a job with a company called <a href="https://torus.blue">Blue Torus</a>. The pay is good, the hours are amazing and I get to work with cool people. I’m still a ways from my goal of $2000 a month but this is stable income, which is a big improvement from only doing freelancing gigs. I am still freelancing though, the hours for the job are flexible enough that I can do that.</p> <h2 id="productivity">Productivity</h2> <p>One thing I’ve decided to add to my productivity system is my finances. I’ve decided to take my finances a bit more seriously so I can be more responsible with my money. The tool is a bit of a problem right now though. I want to use something like Ledger in combination with ledger-mode because it deals with plaintext files, but I have to learn it a little bit before it can become useful. I was torn between that and using something like GNUCash so I’m trying it out first. If it doesn’t work I’ll use GNUCash or maybe even just org tables.</p> <h2 id="programming">Programming</h2> <p>Unfortunately, I haven’t made too much progress on this. I haven’t been able to consistently work on the projects that I’ve created to up my skills. I did do some work on the <a href="https://github.com/homebaseorg/homebase-prototype">Homebase prototype</a> and I’ve learned more about React and NextJS which my new job requires. It’s not all bad but this will be one of my main focal points moving forward.</p> <h2 id="the-dark-lining-in-the-silver-cloud">The dark lining in the silver cloud</h2> <p>Maybe a week after I started my new job, I was pickpocketed. I didn’t lose any money but I did lose my phone. I got a replacement the next day, it’s a worse phone but it’ll do for now.</p> <hr /> <p>Great month overall.</p> <p>Unlike last month I would mind if every month went like this. Can’t be losing my phone every month.</p></article> ]]></description>
		</item>
<item>
		<title>May 2023 Review</title>
		<link>https://lawrencelogoh.com/blog/may_2023_review.html</link>
		<pubDate>2023-06-20</pubDate>
		<guid>https://lawrencelogoh.com/blog/may_2023_review.html</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[    <article><p>This was another rough month. To a lesser extent than last month, but still…</p> <p>My main focus was work and writing exams this month. It was less rough because the exams are spaced out differently and they don’t take as much time as a class.</p> <h2 id="productivity">Productivity</h2> <p>I’ve become more productive but I’ve noticed that most of the things I’m doing aren’t directly related to my goals. Things are getting done but not the most important things. I didn’t think I’d have this problem so it’s something to think about.</p> <p>I don’t have anything else to say about other areas of my life. Things have been the same since last month. I don’t think that’s a good thing.</p> <hr /> <p>Yes, you didn’t read the date wrong. I almost didn’t want to write this but I had to. I’ll write the next one on time and we’ll continue like nothing happened.</p></article> ]]></description>
		</item>
<item>
		<title>Money vs Passion</title>
		<link>https://lawrencelogoh.com/blog/money_vs_passion.html</link>
		<pubDate>2023-12-10</pubDate>
		<guid>https://lawrencelogoh.com/blog/money_vs_passion.html</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[    <article><p>Growing up, I’ve always had a unique relationship with money. While I didn’t grow up “rich”, money was never a thing I had to think about. Sometimes I got what I wanted, other times my parents told me it was outside of their budget and I understood(even if I was mad).</p> <p>I don’t think I’m unique in feeling like this, but some part of me felt like trying to make money with programming was bad. It felt like programming with the express goal of making money was bad. In my mind, programming was this pure “thing” and using it solely to pursue money dirtied it.I even saw people who did that as dirty as well. Sure they could do what they wanted but I cringed whenever they would call themselves programmers or god forbid “software engineers” because they weren’t “real programmers” <del>like me</del>.</p> <p>Keep in mind, this is me at around fourteen years old. Eleven years have passed since then and I’ve changed a lot. I’ve come to understand that wanting to make a lot of money isn’t a bad thing. If programming helps someone achieve that, then more power to them.</p> <p>A few days ago I read an article by Pieter Levels titled <a href="https://levels.io/how-i-build-my-minimum-viable-products/">“How I build my minimum viable products”</a>. I read it because I’ve been thinking about ways to make money with programming and he seemed to be good at doing just that. I think it’s a helpful article and if you want to do a similar thing to what he’s doing, go read it. While reading the article, two sentences caught my attention.</p> <blockquote> <p>Programming is not my passion. Making stuff is my passion.</p> </blockquote> <p>I felt a little uncomfortable reading that. The making stuff part I can understand because, of course, I want to make stuff, but I think I still agreed with fourteen-year-old me on some level. So I decided to sit down and think about why it made me feel uncomfortable beyond it dirtying programming and I came up with an answer that felt right.</p> <blockquote> <p>Should I sell out?</p> </blockquote> <p>It felt like it was an either or choice. One thing that helped me changed my mind was this stream by George Hotz titled <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=N2bXEUSAiTI">“what is programming? (noob lessons!)”</a>. In the stream he makes a distinction between a thing he calls “High Brow Software Engineering” and another he calls “Translating business requirements into code”. We call both of them programming but they’re different things. I think the latter is self explanatory but the former is best explained by George <a href="https://youtu.be/N2bXEUSAiTI?si=ghH_2nW3MVSWIfJk&amp;t=1260">here</a>.</p> <p>The conclusion I came to was that I can do both. One can be a thing I do for work and the other can be something I do for fun. The thing that I will keep in mind is that while I am “selling out” I’m still going to be selective in the things that I build. I’m not going to build yet another AI tool that uses OpenAI’s APIs in a really basic way for example.</p> <p>While the things I’m passionate about may not bring money in the short term, I think I should still do them because I enjoy them. On the other hand, I need money so I will “sell out” at least for a time and create products that people want to use. The hope will be that in the future I can spend more time on the programming I enjoy and less time on the one I don’t enjoy.</p> <p>From now on you’ll be seeing a lot of projects that I will be working on. Some of them will be products designed to make me money and some will be things I think are cool. While I’m doing this, I will be on the lookout for something that is both fun and profitable.</p> <p>Hopefully I find it.</p></article> ]]></description>
		</item>
<item>
		<title>November 2023 Review</title>
		<link>https://lawrencelogoh.com/blog/nov_2023_review.html</link>
		<pubDate>2023-11-30</pubDate>
		<guid>https://lawrencelogoh.com/blog/nov_2023_review.html</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[    <article><p>This month was for resting. I didn’t push myself as hard as I could on most days. I felt a little guilty because of this, but I think it’s good. It was a well earned rest after going full throttle for quite a while.</p> <h2 id="productivity">Productivity</h2> <p>I wasn’t as productive as I was last month but because my baseline productivity has increased, I’m not too worried about this.</p> <h2 id="relationships">Relationships</h2> <p>I spent time with the people I cared about when I could, so I’m good on this front.</p> <h2 id="programming">Programming</h2> <p>I’ve had time to think about this quite a bit and to decide my direction going forward. I know it sounds confusing but you’ll understand after you read the next article.</p> <p>In terms of doing programming itself, I didn’t program as much as last month.</p> <h2 id="money">Money</h2> <p>Money was a little tight this month, but I was able to stay afloat. I’ll also be talking about it in the next article.</p> <p>Oh I did create a whole system to manage my finances though. I call it the Personal Finance System(PFS). I won’t go into it right now because I still consider it a work in progress but it’s basically a system to manage money based on sound advice but also catering to my specific idiosyncrasies.</p> <h2 id="other-skills">Other skills</h2> <p>I didn’t put as much effort into this like everything else, but I’ve found a way to schedule them in my calendar as they are becoming a bit much to manage. I’m sure I’ll pick up others along the way but they will be put on the back burner until I drop any of the current ones.</p> <hr /> <p>Decent month overall. I think I’m ready to start going hard again but I’ll try not to get too close to the sun 🙂.</p></article> ]]></description>
		</item>
<item>
		<title>October 2023 Review</title>
		<link>https://lawrencelogoh.com/blog/oct_2023_review.html</link>
		<pubDate>2023-11-17</pubDate>
		<guid>https://lawrencelogoh.com/blog/oct_2023_review.html</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[    <article><p>It was tough balancing, school, work and freelance gigs but I managed to do it. Now school is off the plate so we can redirect energy elsewhere.</p> <h2 id="productivity">Productivity</h2> <p>This is the most productive I’ve ever been. However, it was mostly fueled by coffee, red bull and dread. So in other words, not sustainable. A strange thing that has happened as a result of this is that I feel like I’ve “unlocked” something. I’ll have to think about it a bit more but my it feels like my baseline productivity has improved as a result.</p> <h2 id="relationships">Relationships</h2> <p>I was busy but not busy enough to not make time. I could’ve done better. I’ll try to do better next month.</p> <h2 id="programming">Programming</h2> <p>I’ve done a lot of programming this month. I’m not sure if that translates to me being better but it’s something.</p> <h2 id="money">Money</h2> <p>I made some extra money this month. It came with added stress but it was worth it. Now that I’m done with school I can put in more effort into getting money.</p> <h2 id="other-skills">Other skills</h2> <p>I’m still learning how to make music with Ardour. It might be the hardest thing I’ve had to learn. It just feels foreign to me and there’s so much to take in.</p> <p>I’m also learning how to draw and UI/UX design. I’m learning drawing for fun but I’m learning UI/UX design to be able to build web apps from end to end instead of just being able to code a design.</p> <hr /> <p>Overall, good month. I’m still reeling from the roller coaster that was last month but I think I’ll be 100% soon and things will be back to normal.</p></article> ]]></description>
		</item>
<item>
		<title>September 2023 Review</title>
		<link>https://lawrencelogoh.com/blog/sept_2023_review.html</link>
		<pubDate>2023-10-15</pubDate>
		<guid>https://lawrencelogoh.com/blog/sept_2023_review.html</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[    <article><p>This month was rough. I say “this month” but clearly some of it bled into October. My main focus was school. Specifically, finishing my final year project. I also took on some extra work, thinking I could handle it, and I did. But I had to pull a few all-nighters to make sure everything got done. That took a huge toll on me physically and mentally.</p> <hr /> <p>Hopefully this is the worst month of this year.</p> <p>Let’s try again.</p></article> ]]></description>
		</item>

</channel>
</rss>
