<rss version="2.0">
<channel>		 
  <title>Lawrence Logoh's blog</title>
  <link>https://www.lawrencelogoh.xyz</link>
  <description>Blog posts on Lawrence Logoh's blog</description>
  <generator></generator>

<item>
		<title>I quit Advent of Code 2021</title>
		<link>https://www.lawrencelogoh.xyz/blog/2022-01-18-aoc-quit.html</link>
		<pubDate>Sat, 08 Jan 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		<guid>https://www.lawrencelogoh.xyz/blog/2022-01-18-aoc-quit.html</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<article><p>I did it for good reasons this time I promise.</p><p>The main reason I’m quitting is I really do not have the time. The way I see it, I don’t have the skills to solve the puzzles as quickly as I would like. It takes me way too long to solve the problems and I assume the complexity will continue to increase at least to a certain point.</p><p>I have work(National Service) now, which takes around 12 hours of my time. I also have side projects(coming soon) that will take up most of the extra time. So I’ll give up on last year’s advent of code. By the time this year ends, I should be able to handle the next one.</p></article>]]></description>
		</item><item>
		<title>“Don’t you want to become a professional developer?”</title>
		<link>https://www.lawrencelogoh.xyz/blog/2021-12-18-professional-developer.html</link>
		<pubDate>Sat, 18 Dec 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		<guid>https://www.lawrencelogoh.xyz/blog/2021-12-18-professional-developer.html</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<article><p>I started learning programming about 11 years ago. It was 2010, and I had just started having somewhat regular internet access through internet cafes. I also started using facebook at the time. Naturally, I already knew about the story of Facebook. Combine this with the fact that I’ve been told I’m smart my whole life. What you get is an arrogant 12 year old who thinks he’s going to be the next Mark Zuckerberg.</p><p>Obviously, that didn’t happen and I can think of many good reasons why it didn’t but that’s not the point. I don’t really regret not becoming “successful” in the way that I thought about it at the time. What I regret is the fact that I didn’t do anything. Most of my teenage years were spent on escapism. In terms of programming, all I did was consume programming content and try out stuff. If I could do or learn about something I thought was cool, I was satisfied.</p><p>When I turned 19, I kind of had a breakdown. I looked back at my life and felt I had wasted my time and not worked on my skills. Which was mostly true. On top of that, I had failed Mathematics in high school so I had to rewrite it again, if I wanted to get into University. I didn’t want to go to University. The problem was even if I thought I was a decent programmer at the time, I had nothing to show for it. My parents managed to convince me to go to remedial school for a year to rewrite the papers I didn’t do to well in. After writing them, my family and family friends also managed to convince me to go to University. The problem was in my mind University was for certain kinds of people. The kind who hadn’t started programming when they were 12. And here I was going to University.</p><p>I just finished getting my<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Higher_National_Diploma">HND</a>this year. Some part of me is still disappointed that I went to University. I could continue and get my degree or do something else. I’m not sure what decision I’ll make.</p><p>Within the time I was in University I had a lot of time to think. And I thought about a lot of things. One thing I spent a significant amount of time on is something I can only describe as “Becoming myself”. I felt that I had lost the essence of who I was by trying to become something I wasn’t.</p><p>I remember having a conversation with an acquaintance this year. A friend had referred him to me because he had some bugs in a programming project he was working on. Before he told me his problems he asked a series of questions just so he could know if I could help him. Like what my “stack” was and what programming languages I knew among other things. I forget what exactly he asked and what I answered with but it made him ask an interesting question.</p><blockquote><p>“Don’t you want to become a professional developer?”</p></blockquote><p>It was interesting because I had never thought about being a developer like that but I immediately knew what the answer was.</p><blockquote><p>“No”</p></blockquote><p>This didn’t mean I didn’t want to be a good developer or programmer. I had just never really thought of myself that way. As<em>only</em>a developer or programmer. I wanted to do cool stuff, and programming was just one of those things.</p><p>I felt like I had some idea about how to “become myself” now. The problem is unlike being a “professional developer”, there didn’t seem to be a standard road map for being a generalist. Everyone seems to have taken their own path, so I’ve made plans for my own.</p><p>I’m not sure where it’ll lead me. Hopefully to success( money :) ) but I think I’ll be satisfied so long I get to work on and do cool stuff.</p></article>]]></description>
		</item><item>
		<title>Advent of Code 2021</title>
		<link>https://www.lawrencelogoh.xyz/blog/2021-12-02-aoc.html</link>
		<pubDate>Thu, 02 Dec 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		<guid>https://www.lawrencelogoh.xyz/blog/2021-12-02-aoc.html</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<article><p>I think the first time I heard of<a href="https://adventofcode.com/">Advent of Code</a>was in 2018. I had just started University at the time and I had been programming for about 8 years at that point. I didn’t have the confidence to take it on. Last year it came on my radar again, but I gave up after some resistance. “I have better things to do” I thought.</p><p>This year however I’m doing it.</p><p>This time I’m doing to get my Go skills to an OK level. By “OK level” I mean it should give me the skills to start a project or two and learn as I<em>go</em>along. It should also be fun as I generally enjoy puzzles.</p><p>I’m not planning on competing with anyone so I’ll take my time, I’ll probably finish it next month.</p><p>Look at my bad solutions at<a href="https://github.com/lawrencelogoh/aoc-2021" class="uri">https://github.com/lawrencelogoh/aoc-2021</a></p></article>]]></description>
		</item><item>
		<title>Hello, World!</title>
		<link>https://www.lawrencelogoh.xyz/blog/2021-10-21-hello-world.html</link>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 Oct 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
		<guid>https://www.lawrencelogoh.xyz/blog/2021-10-21-hello-world.html</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<article><p>Hello, World!</p><p>I took too long to build this site but I’m finally “done”<a href="#fn1" class="footnote-ref" id="fnref1" role="doc-noteref"><sup>1</sup></a>. I’m sure writing articles will be harder than building this but they won’t be as slow.</p><p>I have a lot of interests and this blog will reflect that. The constant one will be technology and there will be other things related and unrelated.</p><p>If you ever want to complain or tell me why I’m wrong on anything, email me at<a href="mailto:lawrence.logoh@gmail.com">lawrence.logoh@gmail.com</a></p><section class="footnotes" role="doc-endnotes"><hr><ol><li id="fn1" role="doc-endnote"><p>Obviously there will be improvements, but it works.<a href="#fnref1" class="footnote-back" role="doc-backlink">↩︎</a></p></li></ol></section></article>]]></description>
		</item>
</channel>
</rss>
